ASAPH **IRABARUTA**

KG 673 St 俞

+250784019340

asaphirabaruta1@gmail.com

✓

LinkedIn Profile in

Website



SUMMARY

I am a software engineer who is interested in problem-solving. I have worked on multiple web development projects using JavaScript, Python, SQL, and other technologies. Apart from this, I enjoy giving back to the community by volunteering in teaching programming courses. For more about me, you can visit my personal website.



EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Technology | Carnegie Mellon University August 2022 – May 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | University of Rwanda September 2017 – January 2022



EXPERIENCE

PWSA Hackathon | Programming Workshop for Scientists in Africa (PWSA)

August 2019 – September 2019

In this hackathon organized by Glasgow University, me and my 2 colleagues, were prized for the $\mathbf{1}^{st}$ position whereby we created a new programming language compiler using python.

Backend Developer | Imali.biz

April 2020 - August 2021

I was a backend developer of this e-commerce system whereby:

- I revamped the relational database by indexing using SQL. And because of this, new database was able to retrieve data faster.
- I built REST APIs using node.js. And tested them using Postman.

Full Stack Developer | Student's Documents Management System August 2021 – January 2022

In my undergraduate, I developed a system to manage Students' documents. This replaced a paper-based system that was inefficient and prone to damage.

- I developed the frontend part of the system with React.js and material UI.
- I developed REST APIs using node.js.
- I designed a relational database using SQL.

X

SKILLS

- Programming Skills (Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, React, Node, SQL, MongoDB)
- Data Science and ML (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit learn)



ACTIVITIES

I enjoy spending time reading books and blogs about the latest programming technologies. In my free time, I build personal projects and solve programming challenges.